Hi everyone, welcome back to our listening course.
During many years of teaching IELTS, I realised
that many students have difficulties with the question
type of labelling a map or diagram, because
they are often confused while listening and don't
know which part the speaker is talking about.
If they miss a question, they may not
know what to do next to continue listening.
In the worst case, they end up getting
all incorrect answers.
In today's lesson, I am going to help
you increase the percentage of correct answers to
80% with just a few basic steps.
In this lesson, we are going to review
the format and key features of labelling a
map or diagram questions in the IELTS listening
test, understand and apply effective steps to answer
labelling a map or diagram question, recognise common
mistakes such as misspelling words, not checking your
predictions, or not being able to identify distractors
involving active or passive voice, and finally, apply
useful tips to improve your score in this
type of exercise in the listening test.
By the end of this lesson, you will
feel more confident to tackle labelling a map
or diagram exercises in the IELTS listening test.
So let's get started.
In the first format of labelling a map
or diagram, you will be given options, for
example from A to E.
Your task is to choose them from a
box and write the corresponding letters in the
map or diagram.
In the second format, there are not any
given options for you to choose from.
Instead, you have to listen to the recording
and fill in the correct information in the
blanks.
One important reminder is that the questions do
not always come in a top-down or
clockwise order.
The answers might come in the same order
as the information is presented in the recording.
The steps for labelling a map and labelling
a diagram are quite similar.
For both exercise types, you will need to
identify the keywords or fixed locations and make
predictions before listening and filling in the correct
answers.
We will go over the steps for each
type in the following videos with practice exercises.
See you soon!